

Zahir Iqbal

Marketing | Strategy | Growth

Personal Profile:

Determined and earnest professional with 3 years experience in E-Commerce Sales and Marketing. Keen on transforming acquired knowledge into actions that optimize revenue for the company. With a strong willingness to learn, prepared to contribute to increased on-site conversion performance and optimize methods for efficiency.

Contact Me:

Mobile: +971 56 8361237

Address: PO Box 16733 Dubai, UAE

Email: zahir.mohdiqbal@gmail.com

Website: www.zahirux.com

Linkedin: www.linkedin.com/in/zahir97/

Skills:

- Microsoft Office (Excel, Word, PowerPoint, Visio)
- JIRA
- Tableau
- Market Research
- · Google Analytics
- Google Data Studio
- MailChimp
- SOL
- · Hypothesis Testing
- Oualtrics

Education:

American University of Sharjah

Major - Finance/ Minor - MIS January 2017 to December 2020

 Awarded "Exceeds expectation in critical thinking" for "Fundamental of Management"

Languages:

- English Native or Bilingual Proficiency
- Hindi Limited Working Proficiency
- Arabic Elementary Proficiency
- Spanish Elementary Proficiency

Work Experience:

Marketing Operations Specialist

Talabat MENA

Aug 2022 to Present

- Mapped over 16 marketing channels' actual budget and best estimate budget for 8 markets (MENA) to Big Query to produce an automated Tableau report.
- Liaise with 8 local marketing teams to understand the competitive landscape within their respective market, and inform regional team on the same.
- Assist with adhoc analysis of marketing channels and report on significant variance on key metrics such as forecasts, acquisitions, CPA, frequency, budgets, and MA.
- Support in updating run-rates of acquisitions and orders to compare against target/best estimate for all 8 markets in MENA region.

Business Development Executive

noon Food

July 2021 to April 2022

- Established key acquisition metrics to efficiently track performance and ensure targets are achieved
- Led Dubai acquisition operation and structured strategies with Business Development Manager to drive increased supply
- Market mapped over 2000+ restaurant leads to a noon Food platform
- Generated 1000+ leads utilizing growth hacking tools for increased assortment in various food categories.
- Increased acquisition team's performance by implementing a Sales Rep onboarding tracker for Sharjah, Abu Dhabi, and Dubai.

Digital Trade Intern - Beauty Category

Al-Tayer (Ounass)

February 2021 to May 2021

- Analyze key commercial KPIs for Beauty Category across 5 markets such as Qatar, KSA, UAE, Oman, and Kuwait
- Assisted in category brand-level budget forecasting with Buying Team for effective stock replenishment
- Assisted Digital Trade Manager with activations calendar
- Liaise with Digital Marketing, Merchandising, and Customer Care Teams to ensure increased conversion for listed brands within the category.

Certifications:

- Google AdWords
- Online Marketing Foundations Linkedin
- Complete Digital Marketing Udemy
- Growth hacking with Digital Marketing Udemy
- CXL Growth Hacking Mini-Degree